the matrix is one of the greatest
metaphors ever machines invented to make
human life easier end up enslaving
humanity this is the most common theme
in dystopian science fiction why is this
fear so universal so compelling is it
because we really believe that our
toaster and our notebook will end up as
our mechanical overlords of course not
this is not a future that we fear but a
past that we are already living
supposedly governments were invented to
make human life easier and safer but
governments always end up enslaving
humanity that which we create to quote
serve us ends up ruling us the US
government by and for the people now
imprisons millions takes half the
national income by force / regulates
punishes tortures slaughters foreigners
invades countries overthrows governments
imposes 700 imperialistic bases overseas
inflates the currency and crashes future
generations with massive debts that
which we create to serve us ends up
ruling us the problem with the state as
servant thesis is that it is
historically completely false
both empirically and logically the idea
that states were voluntarily invented by
citizens to enhance their own security
is utterly untrue before governments in
tribal times human beings could only
produce what they consumed there was no
excess production of food or other
resources thus there was no point owning
slaves because the slave could not
produce
any excess that could be stolen by the
master if a horse pulling a plow can
only produce enough additional food to
feed the horse
there's no point hunting capturing and
breaking in a horse
however when agricultural improvements
allowed for the creation of excess crops
suddenly it became highly advantageous
to own human beings when cows began to
provide excess milk and meat owning cows
became worthwhile the earliest
governments and empires were in fact a
ruling class of slave hunters who
understood that because human beings
could produce more than they consumed
they were worth hunting capturing
breaking in and owning the earliest
Egyptian and Chinese empires were in
reality human farms where people were
hunted captured domesticated and owned
like any other form of livestock due to
technological and methodological
improvements the slaves produced enough
access that the labor involved in
capturing and keeping them represented
only a small subset of their total
productivity the ruling class the
farmers kept the large portion of that
access while handing out gifts and
payments to the brutalizing class the
police slave hunters and general sadists
and the propagandizing class the priests
intellectuals and artists this situation
continued for thousands of years until
the 16th to 17th centuries when again
massive improvement in agricultural
organization and technology created the
second wave of excess productivity the
enclosure movement reorganized and
consolidated farmland resulting in five
to ten times more crops creating a new
class of industrial workers displays
from the country and huddling in the new
cities this enormous agricultural excess
was the basis of the capital that drove
the Industrial Revolution the Industrial
Revolution did not arise because the
ruling class wanted to free their serfs
but rather because they realized how
additional quote liberties could make
their livestock astoundingly more
productive when cows are placed in very
confining stalls they beat their heads
against the walls resulting in injuries
and infections thus farmers now give
them more room not because they want to
set their cows free but rather because
they want greater productivity and lower
costs the next stop after free-range is
not freedom the rise of state capitalism
in the 19th century was actually the
rise of free-range serfdom additional
liberties were granted to the human
livestock not with the goal of setting
them free but rather with the goal of
increasing their productivity of course
intellectuals artists and priests were
and are well paid to conceal this
reality the great problem of modern
human livestock ownership is the
challenge of enthusiasm state capitalism
only works when the entrepreneurial
spirit drives creativity and
productivity in the economy however
excess productivity always creates a
larger state and swells the ruling
classes and their dependence which eats
into the motivation for additional
productivity taxes and regulations rise
state debt future farming increases
and living standards slow and decay
depression and despair begin to spread
as the reality of being owned sets in
for the general population the solution
to this is additional propaganda
antidepressant medications superstition
Wars moral campaigns of every kind the
creation of quote enemies the
inculcation of patriotism collective
fears paranoia about outsiders and
immigrants and so on it is essential to
understand the reality of the world when
you look at a map of the world you are
not looking at countries but farms you
are allowed certain liberties limited
property ownership movement rights
freedom of association and occupation
not because your government approves of
these rights in principle since it
constantly violates them but rather
because free-range livestock it's so
much cheaper to own and so much more
productive it is important
to understand the reality of ideologies
state capitalism socialism communism
fascism democracy these are all
livestock management approaches some
work well for long periods state
capitalism and some work very badly
communism they all fail eventually
because it is immoral and irrational to
treat human beings as livestock the
recent growth of freedom in China India
and Asia is occurring because the local
state farmers have upgraded their
livestock management practices they have
recognized that putting the cows in a
larger stall provides the rulers more
milk and meat rulers have also
recognized that if they prevent you from
fleeing the farm you will become
depressed inert and unproductive a serf
is the most productive when he imagines
he is free vast your rulers must provide
you the illusion of freedom in order to
harvest you most effectively that you
are allowed to leave but never to real
freedom only to another farm because the
whole world is a farm they will prevent
you from taking a lot of money they will
bury you
in endless paperwork they will restrict
your right to work but you are a quote
free to leave due to these difficulties
very few people do leave but the
illusion of mobility is maintained if
only one out of a thousand cows escapes
but the illusion of escaping
significantly raises the productivity
with the remaining 999 it remains a net
gain for the father you are also kept on
the farm through licensing the most
productive livestock are the
professionals so the rulers fit them
with an electronic dog collar called a
license which only allows them to
practice their trade on their own farm
to further create the illusion of
freedom in certain farms the livestock
are allowed to choose between a few
farmers that the investors present at
best they are given minor choices in how
they are managed
they are never given the choice to shut
down the farm and be truly free
government
our indoctrination pens for livestock
they train children to quote love the
farm and to fear true freedom and
independence and to attack anyone who
questions the brutal reality of human
ownership furthermore they create jobs
for the intellectuals that state
propaganda so relies on the ridiculous
contradictions of statism like religion
can only be sustained through endless
propaganda inflicted upon helpless
children the idea that democracy and
some sort of social contract justifies
the brutal exercise of violent power
over billions is patently ridiculous if
you say to a slave that his ancestors
quote chose slavery and therefore he is
bound by their decisions he will simply
say if slavery is a choice then I choose
not to be a slave this is the most
frightening statement for the ruling
classes which is why they trained their
slaves to attack anyone who dares speak
it statism is not a philosophy state
does not originate from historical
evidence or rational principles statism
is an ex post facto justification for
human ownership statism is an excuse for
violence statism is an ideology and all
ideologies are variations on human
livestock management practices a
religion is pimped out superstition
designed to drug children with fears
that they will endlessly pay to have
quote alleviated nationalism is pimped
out bigotry designed to provoke a
Stockholm Syndrome in the livestock the
opposite
precision is not another superstition
but the truth the opposite of ideology
is not a different ideology but clear
evidence and rational principles the
opposite of superstition and ideology of
statism is philosophy reason and courage
will set us free you do not have to be
livestock take the red pill wake up